<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>




<?xml-model href="Quijas_RelaxNG3.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>

<root>
<title level="book"> The Jungle Book</title>
<author>Rudyard Kipling</author>
<Rdate when="2006-01-16"> January 16, 2006 </Rdate> [eBook #236]<!-- Rdate = Release Date -->
<updated when="2023-05-01"> May 1, 2023</updated>
<language>English</language>

<p>
    It was <time>seven o’clock</time> of a very warm evening in the Seeonee hills when <father>Father Wolf</father> woke up from his day’s rest, scratched himself, yawned, and spread out his paws one after the other to get rid of the sleepy feeling in their tips. <mother>Mother Wolf</mother> lay with her big gray nose dropped across her four tumbling, squealing cubs, and the moon shone into the mouth of the cave where they all lived. “Augrh!” said Father Wolf. “It is time to hunt again.” He was going to spring down hill when a little shadow with a bushy tail crossed the threshold and whined: “Good luck go with you, O Chief of the Wolves. And good luck and strong white teeth go with noble children that they may never forget the hungry in this world.” </p>
    
<p>
    It was the jackal—<henchman>Tabaqui</henchman>, the Dish-licker—and the wolves of India despise <henchman>Tabaqui</henchman> because he runs about making mischief, and telling tales, and eating rags and pieces of leather from the village rubbish-heaps. But they are afraid of him too, because <henchman>Tabaqui</henchman>, more than anyone else in the jungle, is apt to go mad, and then he forgets that he was ever afraid of anyone, and runs through the forest biting everything in his way. Even the tiger runs and hides when little <henchman>Tabaqui</henchman> goes mad, for madness is the most disgraceful thing that can overtake a wild creature. We call it hydrophobia, but they call it dewanee—the madness—and run. </p>
    
<p>
“Enter, then, and look,” said <father>Father Wolf</father> stiffly, “but there is no food here.”
“For a wolf, no,” said <henchman>Tabaqui</henchman>, “but for so mean a person as myself a dry bone is a good feast. Who are we, the Gidur-log [the jackal people], to pick and choose?” He scuttled to the back of the cave, where he found the bone of a buck with some meat on it, and sat cracking the end merrily.
“All thanks for this good meal,” he said, licking his lips. “How beautiful are the noble children! How large are their eyes! And so young too! Indeed, indeed, I might have remembered that the children of kings are men from the beginning.”
Now, <henchman>Tabaqui </henchman>knew as well as anyone else that there is nothing so unlucky as to compliment children to their faces. It pleased him to see Mother and <father>Father Wolf</father> look uncomfortable. </p>
    
<p>
<henchman>Tabaqui</henchman> sat still, rejoicing in the mischief that he had made, and then he said spitefully:
“Shere Khan, the Big One, has shifted his hunting grounds. He will hunt among these hills for the next moon, so he has told me.” </p>
    
<metaData>
    This eBook is for the use of anyone anywhere in the <location where="USA"> United States </location> and most other parts of the world at no cost and with almost no restrictions whatsoever. You may copy it, give it away or re-use it under the terms of the Project Gutenberg License included with this eBook or online at <ref type="xsd:anyURI">www.gutenberg.org</ref>. If you are not located in the <location where="USA">United States</location>, you will have to check the laws of the country where you are located before using this eBook. </metaData>

</root>